Carson Bruce

View at carson.kiwi

I am passionate about creating simple and beautiful apps.

I plan and deliver throughout the entire software development process, from when a project is imagined to its release. I've worked on a number of large projects, demonstrating my experience through a range of roles.

My key attributes include: problem solving, passion to learn and share, open mindedness, and being a team player.

I am at home when working with and sharing JavaScript along with all the technologies and processes it enables.

Get in touch at hello@carson.kiwi (mailto:hello@carson.kiwi)

Experience

Middleware NZ

Mar 2019 - Feb 2022 (2 years 11 months)

I worked at Middleware NZ as a Senior Developer. My focus shifted more towards API and microservice development aiming to broaden my technical experience. Many projects gave me practice across a variety of teams, technology and process. I was able to adapt to each unique challenge and achieve positive outcomes for internal and external clients. A good part of my time at Middleware NZ was focused delivering an internal product, the Open Banking Accelerator and Engagement Platform, which was successfully sold and implemented within multiple banking clients.

See the Projects section and some of the work I was apart of with Middleware NZ.

Properly

Nov 2017 - Mar 2019 (1 year 4 months)

I joined Properly with a team of 14, working across the world to provide tools and people to property owners and managers. After achieving our Series-A funding I became the lead for the frontend team, together owning the multiple web apps of Properly. Beyond this role, I was involved with more of our engineering, design, and test team activities. This included: Web/Service implementation design, Full stack development, UX design, UI test automation, CI pipelines, Infrastructure design, and Infrastructure as code.

Solnet

Aug 2012 - Nov 2017 (5 years 3 months)

I started with Solnet after graduating, joining the delivery team. I gained experience with a variety of clients, first as a front end developer, then as others: Devops developer, API developer, Automation tester, and UX designer. Later at my time in Solnet I mentored team members in Javascript tooling and practices, through 1-on-1's and group presentations.

See the Projects section and some of the work I've done with Solnet.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering, Software Engineering, First Class Honours

Victoria University of Wellington *2007-2012*

Projects

Open Banking Accelerator Product

Glueware

The Open Banking Accelerator (OBA) product provides a standards conformant set of APIs banks can publish. With a small internal team, we created the product building on previous years experience within the Open Banking domain. My role included delegating design, implementation and testing tasks along with reviewing and supporting other work in the team.

- Owned technical leadership of microservice development and testing.
- · Promoted strong testing culture throughout team.
- Succeeded to prove value through multiple trials with banks.
- Applied feedback from customers to improve experience and quality of the product.
- · Worked closely with Product Owners to ensure team tasks and focus was aligned.
- Designed scalable and modular application using cloud and microservice patterns.

NZ COVID Pass Integration

MoH

This project was part of the Ministries COVID response to bring a verifiable COVID pass to people living or visiting New Zealand. Challenges included ensuring forecasted demand was handled and ensuring the APIs were appropriately secured given their sensitive nature. My role involved helping support more junior members of the team and aligning the work of the team with the delivery.

- Balanced quality of development under high time pressures.
- Enabled other developers and testers within the team by code reviews and pair programming.
- Communicated with client and other venders to ensure alignment of delivery.
- Supported design and achieved implementation of a highly available solution.

Lending and Onboarding

BNZ

I joined a product team at BNZ to help transform their Lending and Onboarding systems, aiming to improve the experience for customers and bank users. This transformation was supported by a new way of delivery, promoting more modular systems design and implementation with supporting platforms and dev-ops processes. I shared the lead for the Front-end implementation of two major applications and a component library.

Lead app design and development using a new front end technology.

- Promoted and adapted a UI component library for multiple applications.
- · Guided Front-end developers through best practices, process and tooling.
- Guided UI Integration testers through best practices, process and tooling.

Employment Agreement Builder

Ministry of Business and Innovation and Employment

EAB is an application for small to medium businesses to create new Employment agreements while learning about employment law with easy-to-digest content. EAB exceeded its objectives and was built, tested, and delivered in three months.

- Practiced BDD and TDD creating a suite of feature-complete integration and unit tests.
- Created a reusable forms solution, reused for a second MBIE Policy Builder app.
- Promoted a full stack Javascript solution supported by docker.
- Implemented Node.js micro service handling 10x expected load.
- Implemented a pipeline that performed automated testing and releases.

Interests

Netball		Running		Cycling
	Photography		Gaming	

hello@carson.kiwi

GitHub https://github.com/Kauabunga Linkedin https://nz.linkedin.com/in/carsonbruce